Hello everyone and welcome to English Pawn.
My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and it's
the start of a very new year so we
have some interesting vocabulary
for you today about the new year.
That's right so we
are starting a new year.
Why don't we just jump
right into this dialogue.
Let's see what's going on
and we'll be back in a bit.
It's almost midnight.
We're about to start a brand new year.
I know it's so exciting. A new
year is always like a clean slate.
A fresh start to accomplish any
dreams, objectives, and goals.
Do you have a new
year's resolution?
I was thinking about it but
I'm never able to keep my
new year's resolutions. Last year for
example I joined a gym and only went twice.
Yeah I know what you mean.
That's why this year I am keeping
things more simple. Maybe
like getting together with
friends I haven't seen
in a long time or doing
some volunteering work.
That seems reasonable.
We should get together
and watch the ball drop
in Times Square. Sure
as long as you don't try
to kiss me at midnight. Well we
can't break tradition. It's bad luck.
All right so we've
prepared a couple of
different words for you
on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. All right the first the
first word we have is actually a phrase.
We have this phrase brand new.
Something is a brand new thing.
That's right we said that
we are starting a brand
new year and that's just another
way of saying completely new.
So I want a brand new bicycle.
It means I want a new
bicycle from the store.
Not one from the
garage. That's right so it's
something completely
new never been used.
So we're starting a brand
new year and we're saying it's
exciting because it's a
great opportunity like
having a clean
slate. So a clean slate.
Now this is an interesting
phrase because you may not know
what a slate is but basically
it means that you start
from the very beginning.
So there's no history.
There's no nothing that
you have to worry about.
You start completely
new. That's a clean slate.
That's right so just
imagine you're in class
and you have the whiteboard
or the chalkboard and
you just erase everything
and then you start again.
That's kind of what it
means to have a clean slate.
A new start. Exactly and
so we have a clean slate.
We need to talk about
what we will do with the
clean slate and so one
person asks the other.
Do you have any new years
resolutions? That's right.
So this is one of the
most popular things during
the new years is people
make a new year's resolution.
So a resolution is
something that you have
decided you will do. I
have many resolutions.
I will learn to play
the piano this year.
So in the new year I will
do this thing. That's right.
So it's basically like a
promise, something that you
promise yourself that
you will do in the new year.
So as you say maybe
start playing the piano.
That's right. So we call
that a resolution or if
we want to be specific we
call it a new year's resolution.
Now at the very end of the dialogue we
heard another phrase. This is quite strange.
They want to kiss at midnight and then one
person says well we can't break tradition.
That's right. To break a tradition or to
break tradition and that basically means to
not do something that
we usually do. All right.
So you can follow a
tradition. That means that you
do the same thing
maybe every year.
But if you break tradition that means
you don't do what you are expected to do.
So remember that verb is to break,
break tradition. That's right. All right.
So let's review this vocab.
Let's listen to the dialogue again.
It's almost midnight. We're
about to start a brand new year.
I know. It's so exciting.
A new year is always like a
clean slate. A fresh start to
accomplish any dreams,
objectives and goals.
Do you have a new
year's resolution?
I was thinking about it but
I'm never able to keep my
new year's resolutions.
Last year for example I
joined a gym and only went
twice. Yeah I know what you mean.
That's why this year I am
keeping things more simple.
Maybe like getting together with friends
I haven't seen in a long time or doing
some volunteering work.
That seems reasonable.
We should get together
and watch the ball drop
in Times Square. Sure
as long as you don't try to
kiss me at midnight. Well we
can't break tradition. It's bad luck.
All right so let's take
a look at those phrases
now on Fluency
Builder. Fluency Builder.
So there's a phrase in
here that I use all the time.
We heard about this resolution to go to
the gym more often and the person said you
know I never really go to the gym and the
other said you know I know what you mean.
Yeah that's right she says yeah
I know what you mean and so
basically we use this
when you agree with the
person you understand
what they are saying.
Yeah it's almost like saying
I had the same experience.
So maybe I also belong to a gym
and I never go to that gym just like you.
So means I know what you
mean. I have the same problem.
That's right so you can
just agree with someone
completely agree with
someone by saying yeah I know
what you mean or I
know what you mean.
I know what you mean. All
right so well this year we want to
keep things a little bit
more simple and we said
well maybe like getting together with
friends I haven't seen in a long time.
All right so think about this
to get together with friends.
Loss of words there but
you can see friends but to
get together means to
be social with to hang out
with to do things
together but it's not very
specific it's a nice way to say
just to be with your friends.
That's right so
maybe you are going
with your friends out maybe
shopping maybe to the movies.
So you say yeah I'm
gonna get together with
my friends later on this
afternoon. All right so
we can get together
with friends as a resolution
that's something we want
to do in the near future
but for now we're going
to get together and watch
the ball drop in Times Square
that's the new year's plan.
That's right so it may it may seem strange
it's not actually a phrasal verb or a
colloquial phrase. There
is actually a ball that
goes down as the
countdown begins to midnight
and once it completely
disappears then you know
you celebrate the new
year so you actually see this
big round ball coming
down in Times Square.
Yeah it's a way to count
down to the new year so
people often say 10, 9,
8, 7 to the countdown and
the ball will drop and that
means it's the new year.
So this is something
that we refer to and
then we talk about when
we want to discuss the
new year so we'll watch the
ball drop together it's an event.
That's right. Okay
so a lot of great
stuff there when we listen
to the dialogue one last time.
It's almost midnight. We're
about to start a brand new year.
I know it's so exciting.
A new year is always like
a clean slate. A fresh start
to accomplish any dreams
objectives and goals.
Do you have a new
year's resolution?
I was thinking about it but
I'm never able to keep my
new year's resolutions.
Last year for example I
joined a gym and only went
twice. Yeah I know what you mean.
That's why this year I am
keeping things more simple.
Maybe like getting together with friends
I haven't seen in a long time or doing
some volunteering work.
That seems reasonable.
We should get together
and watch the ball drop
in Times Square. Sure
as long as you don't
try to kiss me at midnight. Well
we can't break tradition. It's bad luck.
All right so talking
about new years everyone
makes new year's
resolutions and people get
together to watch the
ball drop in Times Square.
Now this is more of
an American thing.
Have you ever experienced
anything different from new years?
Some other type of tradition because also
here they kiss at midnight. That's right.
Well that's a pretty
standard American tradition.
People will get together
and they'll have the TV on.
They'll have a party or
they'll be with friends and they
will maybe watch some
fireworks or watch the TV
as the ball drop. So I've
done both. I've gone out
because sometimes you
go outside. It's very cold
but you go to a bridge or
a park or somewhere public
or the city government
or the state will have
some kind of special
fireworks display.
So then everyone will watch
the fireworks or watch a big
TV screen and then when
it's midnight when it's
the new year then
everyone will kiss.
So everyone will kiss maybe
I mean is it like just between
couples or whoever's available
you kiss whoever's there.
Sometimes it's whoever
is available that's
happened to me where you
turn around and you say oh
hi I don't know you. So
the tradition is you have
to kiss someone at midnight.
So this is for good luck.
Yes. For good luck
in the new year. Yes.
So if you don't kiss someone then
you're kind of breaking the tradition.
I have sad. And it's unlucky.
An interesting way of
celebrating years this is
as we said in the United
States watching the ball
drop kissing someone at
midnight. So we are really
curious to know how you
celebrate your new years
in your country because maybe you have
similar traditions or very different things.
That's right. And I know
some places like Italy
even have special foods
you are supposed to eat
to bring wealth and
prosperity in the new year.
So let us know our
website is EnglishPod.com.
All right. We'll see you guys there.
Bye. Bye.